<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN"
                              "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd" >
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/TR/1999/REC-html-in-xml" xml:lang="en"
	lang="en">
	<head>
                <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="application/xhtml+xml; charset=UTF-8" />
                <!-- HTML5 -->
                <meta charset="UTF-8"/>
		<style type="text/css">
                    .bodyContainer {
    font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;
    text-align: center;
    padding-left: 32px;
    padding-right: 32px;
}

.notebookFor {
    font-size: 18px;
    font-weight: 700;
    text-align: center;
    color: rgb(119, 119, 119);
    margin: 24px 0px 0px;
    padding: 0px;
}

.bookTitle {
    font-size: 32px;
    font-weight: 700;
    text-align: center;
    color: #333333;
    margin-top: 22px;
    padding: 0px;
}

.authors {
    font-size: 13px;
    font-weight: 700;
    text-align: center;
    color: rgb(119, 119, 119);
    margin-top: 22px;
    margin-bottom: 24px; 
    padding: 0px;
}

.citation {
    font-size: 16px;
    font-weight: 500;
    text-align: center;
    color: #333333;
    margin-top: 22px;
    margin-bottom: 24px;
    padding: 0px;
}

.sectionHeading {
    font-size: 24px;
    font-weight: 700;
    text-align: left;
    color: #333333;
    margin-top: 24px;
    padding: 0px;
}

.noteHeading {
    font-size: 18px;
    font-weight: 700;
    text-align: left;
    color: #333333;
    margin-top: 20px;
    padding: 0px;
}

.noteText {
    font-size: 18px;
    font-weight: 500;
    text-align: left;
    color: #333333;
    margin: 2px 0px 0px;
    padding: 0px;
}

.highlight_blue {
    color: rgb(178, 205, 251);
}

.highlight_orange {
    color: #ffd7ae;
}

.highlight_pink {
    color: rgb(255, 191, 206);
}

.highlight_yellow {
    color: rgb(247, 206, 0);
}

.notebookGraphic {
    margin-top: 10px;
    text-align: left;
}

.notebookGraphic img {
    -o-box-shadow:      0px 0px 5px #888;
    -icab-box-shadow:   0px 0px 5px #888;
    -khtml-box-shadow:  0px 0px 5px #888;
    -moz-box-shadow:    0px 0px 5px #888;
    -webkit-box-shadow: 0px 0px 5px #888;
    box-shadow:         0px 0px 5px #888; 
    max-width: 100%;
    height: auto;
}

hr {
    border: 0px none;
    height: 1px;
    background: none repeat scroll 0% 0% rgb(221, 221, 221);
}

		</style>
		<script type="text/javascript">
		    
		</script>
		<title></title>
	</head>
    <body>
        <div class="bodyContainer">
            <div class="notebookFor">
Notebook for
</div>
<div class="bookTitle">
The Life-Changing Magic of Tidying Up (The Life Changing Magic of Tidying Up)
</div>
<div class="authors">
Kondō, Marie
</div>
<div class="citation">
Citation (APA): Kondō, M. (2014). <i>The Life-Changing Magic of Tidying Up (The Life Changing Magic of Tidying Up)</i> [Kindle Android version]. Retrieved from Amazon.com
</div>
<hr />
<div class="sectionHeading">
3. Tidying by category works like magic
</div>
<div class="noteHeading">
Highlight (<span class="highlight_yellow">yellow</span>) - Sentimental items: your parents’ home is not a haven for mementos >  Page 114
</div>
<div class="noteText">
When you think about your future, is it worth keeping mementos of things that you would otherwise forget? We live in the present. No matter how wonderful things used to be, we cannot live in the past. The joy and excitement we feel here and now are more important.
</div>
<div class="noteHeading">
Highlight (<span class="highlight_blue">blue</span>) - Sentimental items: your parents’ home is not a haven for mementos >  Page 116
</div>
<div class="noteText">
If you just stow these things away in a drawer or cardboard box, before you realize it, your past will become a weight that holds you back and keeps you from living in the here and now.
</div>
<div class="noteHeading">
Highlight (<span class="highlight_blue">blue</span>) - Sentimental items: your parents’ home is not a haven for mementos >  Page 118
</div>
<div class="noteText">
It is not our memories but the person we have become because of those past experiences that we should treasure. This is the lesson these keepsakes teach us when we sort them. The space in which we live should be for the person we are becoming now, not for the person we were in the past.
</div>
<div class="noteHeading">
Highlight (<span class="highlight_yellow">yellow</span>) - Reduce until you reach the point where something clicks >  Page 125
</div>
<div class="noteText">
As you put your house in order and decrease your possessions, you’ll see what your true values are, what is really important to you in your life.
</div>
<div class="sectionHeading">
5. The magic of tidying dramatically transforms your life
</div>
<div class="noteHeading">
Highlight (<span class="highlight_blue">blue</span>) - Put your house in order and discover what you really want to do >  Page 175
</div>
<div class="noteText">
At their core, the things we really like do not change over time. Putting your house in order is a great way to discover what they are.
</div>
<div class="noteHeading">
Highlight (<span class="highlight_pink">pink</span>) - Gaining confidence in life through the magic of tidying >  Page 180
</div>
<div class="noteText">
When it comes to the things I own, the clothes I wear, the house I live in, and the people in my life, when it comes to my environment as a whole, although it may not seem particularly special to anyone else, I am confident and extremely grateful to be surrounded by what I love, by things and people that are, each and every one, special, precious, and exceedingly dear to me. The things and people that bring me
</div>
<div class="noteHeading">
Highlight (<span class="highlight_pink">pink</span>) - An attachment to the past or anxiety about the future >  Page 181
</div>
<div class="noteText">
But when we really delve into the reasons for why we can’t let something go, there are only two: an attachment to the past or a fear for the future.
</div>
<div class="noteHeading">
Highlight (<span class="highlight_orange">orange</span>) - An attachment to the past or anxiety about the future >  Page 183
</div>
<div class="noteText">
When one or the other of these thought patterns makes it hard to throw things away, we can’t see what we really need now, at this moment. We aren’t sure what would satisfy us or what we are looking for. As a result, we increase the number of unnecessary possessions, burying ourselves both physically and mentally in superfluous things. The best way to find out what we really need is to get rid of what we don’t.
</div>
<div class="noteHeading">
Highlight (<span class="highlight_yellow">yellow</span>) - Your real life begins after putting your house in order >  Page 204
</div>
<div class="noteText">
As for you, pour your time and passion into what brings you the most joy, your mission in life.
</div>
        </div>
    </body>
</html>
